ICICI BANK LIMITED
SSL Inspection Bypass Risk Assessmentá
Draft Report dated:Aug18, 2026
Type of assessment: SSL Inspection Bypass Risk Assessmentá
Assessor - Mr. Kunal Kumar
Domain Head:
Mr. Vishal Saraswat
Team Leader:
Mr. Manish Srivastava
Manager:
Mr. Omkar Pawar
Advisor:
Mr. Tejbahadur Yadav
Overview:
Request to bypass SSL Inspection for the above URL due to application functionality issues caused by SSL Placement.
Assessment Scope:
The Objective of Assessment is to evaluate implication of granting SSL inspection Bypass for the requested URL, Validate Potential Security Risks arising from reduced Encrypted traffic inspection, assess existing and compensation security controls.
Assessment Objective:
Evaluating Impact of granting SSL Inspection bypass for URL based on submitted justification.
To Identify Potential Risks, Assess Existing and compensating controls.
Business Justification:
The application is connected with CERSAI (Govt. Entity) via API to fetch the customer details which
is required during the onboarding customer journey across Bank. We are connected with CERSAI via Bluecoat Proxy where the SSL is bypassed to fetch the details from CERSAI. As part of the migration from Bluecoat to Zscaler proxy, we would like to have the same configuration in place for the CERSAI API connectivity.
Assessment Process:
1. Business Justification
2. Validation of the requestor URL/FQDN
3. Impact of disabling SSL Inspection
4. Security Risk Introduced by Exception
5. Recommendation based on business need and Security Risks
Assessment performed on below URL:
CAN ID: 7486
Application Name: EVENT HUB
SR. No.
URL
URL Category
Server IP
Risk level identified
1
https://www.ckycindia.in/
Government
10.51.7.205
High
Security Controls Bypass:
SSL Inspection
Proxy Malware/File Inspection
Zscaler DLP
Upload and Download
HTTP Header/Body Inspection
Security Risks:
Malware Payloads
Risk :High
Risk Description:Malicious files may carryávarious typesáofámalwares, such as viruses, worms, Trojans, or ransomware.á
Impact:Malware can compromise the integrity of the system, steal sensitive data, or cause disruptions to normal operations.á
Command and Control Communication
Risk :High
Risk Description:Malicious files oftenáestablisháconnections withácommand and controláservers.á
Impact: Attackers gain remote control over the compromised system, enabling them to execute further malicious activities, exfiltration data, or deployáadditionalápayloads.á
Compensation Controlsá
Following mitigation controls with mail confirmation from respective stakeholders should be attached ináiInsightárequest:á
oááááááááá XDR is installed and running for malicious activity monitoringá
oááááááááá AV is installed and runningá
oááááááááá Latest Patches are appliedá
oááááááááá System harden as per bank policyá
oááááááááá Restrict SSL Bypass to specific FQDN/URL Only
oááááááááá Guardicore Micro-Segmentation Should be placed
oááááááááá DNS Filtering Should be Enabled
oááááááááá Latest TLS Encrypted communication with Certificate Validation
Pls referábelow linkáto raise theáiInsightárequest.á
https://iinsight.icicibankltd.com/exception/riskexceptioná
Acknowledgments
ISG would like to thank respective stake holder and seniors for their co-operation during the assessment.
Note: This SSL Bypass assessment is intended to review risk and evaluate the existence and effectiveness of URL.
